NATHANIEL REISTER

SEATTLE, WA 98119 (206) 643-2841 NATHANIEL.REISTER@GMAIL.COM

NATEREISTER.COM | LINKEDIN.COM/IN/NATEREISTER | GITHUB.COM/NATHAAN92

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm glutton for challenge always dedicating myself to my many ventures and striving to be the embodiment of a well rounded and self capable individual. I graduated cum laude with a double bachelors from SUNY Brockport in 3 years, built a business immediately after my move from New York to Seattle, challenged myself by both managing large commercial and residential development projects while attending a coding boot camp. With the completion of my most recent internship I intend to further excel in the field of Software Development and the manifestation of my goals.

SKILLS

- Languages: C# | Python |
 JavaScript | jQuery, React, Ajax |
 SQL | HTML5 | CSS3
- Databases: MS SQL Server | MySQL | SQLite
- Frameworks: .NET | Web Forms |
 Entity Framework | Django |
 Bootstrap
- Architectural Paradigms: Object-Oriented Concepts | MVC | API | Single-Page Applications

- Methodology: Agile | Scrum
- IDE's: Visual Studio | Visual Studio Code | PyCharm | Microsoft Azure | Node.js | Db Browser
- Non Technical: Project
 Management | Team
 Management | Client Relations |
 Interpersonal Communication |
 Public Speaking | Organizational
 and Process Management |
 Research Driven | Competent in
 Bureaucratic Faculties

WORK HISTORY

OCTOBER 2020-DECEMBER 2020

Software Developer | Prosper IT Consulting | Portland, OR

- Using Entity framework Code First I developed a web application with product models that were integrated further via a relational database and scaffold to provide user manipulation of the database.
 Furthermore I completed user requested changes to UI as well as locate and correct bugs.
- Using Django framework I developed all front and back end components of a web application that collected user preferences from search and survey results then providing them suggestions.

JUNE 2018-CURRENT

Construction Superintendent | Belotti Mchugh Design And Construction Services | Seattle, WA

 Managed and supervised the development of both commercial and residential projects in the greater Seattle Area. The scope of this work included but was not limited to client and government relations, project organization, procurement of labor force and materials, oversite of installation method's, responsibility as primary administrator on site, and workflow and coordination of teams.

OCTOBER 2016-IUNE 2018

Owner and Operator | Fern And Hammer | Seattle, WA

Organized and performed the development of residential spaces. I
procured the materials, labour, and ensure the most relevant building
methods were utilized. Direct client involvement was typical in these
projects as well as constant research into modern building methods. I
performed all administrator duties which included financing,
application for permits, completion of quarterly taxes, and typical
admin duties.

EDUCATION

DECEMBER 2020

Certificate: Full Stack Developer The Tech Academy, Portland, Or

A 1000 hr+ boot camp providing a comprehensive overview of software development with courses in C#, MVC, Python, Django, JavaScript/JQuery, SQL/TSQL(MS SQL Server), HTML5, CSS3, AJAX/XML, Source Control(Git & GitHub), Agile/Scrum Methodologies, OOP, fundamentals of computer technologies.

MAY 2015

Bachelor of Arts: Communications And Political Science SUNY College At Brockport, Brockport, NY Focus of my Double Bachelors

Communications - Mass Media, Interpersonal, Public, Persuasion tactics. Political Sciences - Law and Legal Procedure, Constitutional Law, Comparative Politics.

Noted Achievements

- Dean's List with Honors
- Graduated cum laude
- Resident Assistant
- Cheif Justice in Student Government